Behzad Shayegh Boroujeni

University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

My interest in natural language processing has encouraged me to gain knowledge and experience in this field. Also, I have work experience in feature extraction. Furthermore, I have good knowledge of algorithms, which positively affects my work experiences. In addition to my statistical knowledge, I am familiar with neural networks.

Education

2017-2022 (EXPECTED) Bachelor of Science

Major in Computer Engineering Software Engineering branch, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Tehran GPA: 3.93/4 - 18.41/20 (till now)

Minor in Computer Science School of Mathematics, Statistics and Computer Science, University of Tehran GPA: 4/4 - 19.73/20 (till now)

Relevant Courses

(*: Graduate Course)

Grade/20 Computational Neuroscience * 19.75 Assoc.Prof. Mohammad Ganjtabesh 🗹 Natural Language Processing * 19.1 Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili 🗹 Reinforcement Learning * 20 Prof. Majid Nili 🗹 Statistical Machine Learning * 19.5 Assoc.Prof. Zahra Rezaei Ghahroodi 🗹 Artificial Intelligence Assis.Prof. MohamadAmin Sadeahi 🗹 Statistical Methods 20 Hasan Misaei Engineering Probability and Statistics 19.7 Assis.Prof. Behnam Bahrak 🗹

Research Interests

Computation Neuroscience

L→ Spiking Neural Networks
Natural Language Processing
L→ Text Processing
Cybernetics
L→ Reinforcement Learning

Mob.: +98-9381377391
Email.: behzad.shayegh@ut.ac.ir
Gmail.: behzad.shayegh.b@gmail.com
GitHub.: https://github.com/BehzadShayegh
Web.: https://behzadshayegh.github.io

Spiral 🗹

Projects

2021-Now Spiking Neural Networks Framework

Python Compu-Neuro SNN PyTorch

A python package for spiking neural network simulation using PyTorch on cuda or CPU. This package tries to bring its design as close as possible to biological observations of how the nervous system functions. It will be placed on the official website of the University of Tehran's Computational Neuroscience Research Lab shortly.

Supervisor: Assoc.Prof. Mohammad Ganjtabesh

2020-2021 Persian Address to Postal-Code Convertor PAT ☐

Python NLP NLTK Persian

Persian Address Tracer (PAT) is an intelligent system for converting Persian text of address to postal code. If you are not aware, it is worth mentioning that due to the special conditions in the Persian language and also the lack of standards in addressing in Iran, this is a difficult issue. As far as we know, the PAT system is the most successful and intelligent system available for this issue.

Supervisor: Assis.Prof. MohamadAmin Sadeghi

Work Experience

2019-2020 House Prices Estimation over Tehran 4-Choob ☐

Python Numpy Shapely PostgreSQL Q-GIS PostGIS Map-Processing

4-Choob was a project aimed at automatic house price estimation over Tehran. The result of this project is a housing sales organization whose website is linked. We were the first members to work on this project and I was given the task of extracting features from multiple sources. The result was the extraction of more than 400 efficient price forecasting features. I used vary tools and techniques as there were very different tasks with different concerns; Such as map processing or optimization.

Supervisor: Assis.Prof. MohamadAmin Sadeghi

Books

2020-NOW Discrete Mathematics Persian Book OpenBookshelf ☐

LaTeX Discrete-Mathematics

I am the leader of a group of volunteers who are writing an Persian educational book on discrete mathematics. It is open-source and free for all. It is a charity act and everyone contributes without any expectations. FIPA will be registered soon.

Assoc.Prof. Siamak Mohammadi 🗹

Teaching Assistance Experience

| | | • | | | | | |
|--------------------------------|--------------|---|--|--|--|--|--|
| FALL 2 | 2021 | Engineering Probability and Statistics (Head Teaching Ass | sistant) Assis.Prof. Behnam Bahrak 🗹 | | | | |
| SPRING 2 FALL 2 SPRING 2 | 2020 | Discrete Mathematics (Head Teaching Assistant) | Assoc.Prof. Siamak Mohammadi 🗹 | | | | |
| SPRING 2 | 2021 | Natural Language Processing (Graduate Course) | Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili 🗹 Assis.Prof. Yadollah Yaghoobzadeh 🗹 | | | | |
| SPRING 2 | 2020 | Artificial Intelligence | Dr. Hakimeh Fadaei 🗹 | | | | |
| FALL 2 | 2019 | Engineering Probability and Statistics | Assis.Prof. Behnam Bahrak 🗹 | | | | |
| | 2019 2019 | Discrete Mathematics | Assoc.Prof. Siamak Mohammadi 🗹 | | | | |
| FALL 2 | 2019 | Data Structures and Algorithms | Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili 🗹 | | | | |
| FALL 2 | 2019 | Introduction to Computing Systems and Programming | Assoc.Prof. Manouchehr MoradiSabzevar 🗹 | | | | |
| FALL 2 SPRING 2 | | Engineering Programming | Dr. Noushin Karimian 🗹 | | | | |
| Workshop Mentoring | | | | | | | |
| SPRING | 2020 | Python Tutorial | Amirkabir University | | | | |
| WINTER | 2020 | Data Science Winter School | Khatam University | | | | |
| WINTER | 2020 | Data Science Winter School | University of Tehran | | | | |
| SUMMER | R 201 | 9 Summer of Code, AI Branch ☐ | University of Tehran | | | | |

Written Contents

2021 Applied statistics tutorial in R □

- My Role: Leader
- Usage: Engineering Probability and Statistics Course, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Tehran

Assis.Prof. Behnam Bahrak ☐

2020 Common Mistakes in Discrete Mathematics ☐

- My Role: Supervisor
- Usage: Discrete Mathematics Course, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Tehran

Assoc.Prof. Siamak Mohammadi 🗹

- Usage: Python Tutorial in Amirkabir University

- Usage: Computer Programming Course, Faculty of Engineering Sciences, University of Tehran

Dr. Noushin Karimian 🗹

Python Packages

2021 Add-On Class ☐

2021 Matplotlib Dashboard ☐

2021 Constant Properties Protector ☐

Skills

| | Programming Languages | Python Libraries & Frameworks | Software & DBMSs | Other Tools & Frameworks |
|------------|----------------------------------|--------------------------------------|-----------------------|-----------------------------|
| Expert | Python TeX SQL | Pandas Numpy Spiral | Git LaTeX PostgreSQL | Spreadsheet Markdown |
| Proficient | (R) (Bash) | PyTorch Matplotlib NLTK Scikit-Learn | MySQL PostGIS | HTML CSS Jupyter Colab |
| Familiar | C++ C Java Verilog JavaScript | Keras BindsNET Shapely SciPy.stats | Q-GIS | ReactJS VewJS |
| Beginner | MATLAB C# | Sympy | MongoDB Elasticsearch | Spring |

Notable Course Projects

| SPRING 202 | 1 Text Representation using SNNs (to be continued) ☐ | Computationl Neuroscience Assoc.Prof. Mohammad Ganjtabesh ☐ |
|------------|--|---|
| SPRING 202 | 1 Face Representation using Convolutional SNNs ☐ | Natural Language Processing Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili |
| SPRING 202 | 0 IMDB Spam Ditection using Bert and Elmo ☐ | Natural Language Processing Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili |
| SPRING 202 | O POS Tagging using RNN and HMM ☐ | Natural Language Processing Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili |
| SPRING 202 | 7 Fa2En and En2Fa Neural Machine Translation ☐ | Natural Language Processing Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili |
| SPRING 202 | 7 Feed Forward Neural Network Language Model ☐ | Natural Language Processing Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili ☐ |
| SPRING 202 | Movie Reviews Semantic Analysis using Statistical Langu | age Models |
| SPRING 202 | Persian News Classification using Statistical Language M | odels 🗹 Natural Language Processing Assoc.Prof. Heshaam Faili 🗹 |
| SPRING 201 | 9 Emails Spam Detection using Bag of Words ☐ | Artificial Intelligence Assis.Prof. MohamadAmin Sadeghi ☐ |
| SPRING 201 | 9 Image Classification (CIFAR-10) using CNNs ☐ | Artificial Intelligence Assis.Prof. MohamadAmin Sadeghi ☐ |
| SPRING 201 | 9 Image Classification (MNIST and CIFAR-10) using ML app | _ |
| SPRING 201 | 9 House Price Estimation using Neural Networks ☐ | Artificial Intelligence Assis.Prof. MohamadAmin Sadeghi 🗹 |
| Hands-O | n Series | _ |
| | 1 Understand the parameters in SNNs (9 Parts) ☐ | Computationl Neuroscience Assoc.Prof. Mohammad Ganjtabesh ☐ |
| FALL 202 | O Apply well-known RL algorithms on simulated problems | (5 Parts) ☐ Reinforcement Learning Prof. Majid Nili ☐ |
| FALL 202 | Statistical analysis on datasets and ML models performa | nce(5 Parts) Statistical Machine Learning Assoc.Prof. Zahra Rezaei Ghahroodi |

Refrences

Languages

Persian Native English Fluent

L→ IELTS Score: Overal: 6.5 R: 6.5 | L: 6.5 | S: 6.5 | W: 6.5